And the Israelis were very, very
aggressive in that in that briefing.
>> [music]
>> To the point where they asked me
directly to my face if I was Jewish. And
I said, "I am not recruitable. You
cannot recruit me." When you know that
they're spying on you and they're
actively trying to recruit your
colleagues
to be spies for the Mossad.
I only had direct contact with Israel
one time.
And it was when I first joined the CIA.
I had only been in the CIA 6 weeks.
And I was assigned to give a briefing to
the Israeli intelligence services. I was
one of of about eight analysts. And the
Israelis were very, very aggressive in
that in that briefing. To the point
where they asked me directly to my face
if I was Jewish. And I said, "I am not
recruitable.
You cannot recruit me." I was very angry
about it.
And I went back to the office and my my
boss said to me, "How was the briefing?"
And I said,
"They actually tried to recruit me and
they asked me right to my face in front
of everybody if I was Jewish." And he
laughed and he said, "They do that to
all of us." I think that the United
States has been under great pressure,
great pressure from the Israeli
government from the very beginning of of
Donald Trump's first term as president.
It was my experience at the CIA that
every Israeli prime minister, every time
he would come to the United States,
would ask whoever happened to be
president,
"Please help us overthrow the Iranian
government." Every single time. And
every president said no.
Until Donald Trump. I think that
Benjamin Netanyahu is very persistent. I
think that he is very convincing in many
ways. And I think he convinced Donald
Trump that Iran is some sort of
existential threat
to Israel and that it would be in
somehow in the interest of the United
States to overthrow the Iranian
government. I'm not sure that that is
what's going to happen, but I think that
that's how we got to the place where we
are.
With that said, I don't believe
that
a final decision has been made.
One of the things that I learned at the
CIA was if you really want to understand
what the US intends to do with its
military, watch naval movements.
The United States normally does not
attack anybody unless it has at least
one aircraft carrier battle group in the
area. There is one right now in the
Arabian Sea, the USS Abraham Lincoln.
That is not enough
to wage war on a country of 92 million
people. And so I think that
what this is an effort [music] to
placate the Israelis, number one.
And number two, an effort to put
pressure on the Iranian government
hoping that the Iranian people rise up
and overthrow the government. Every
president
since Richard Nixon
has
has guaranteed the the safety and
protection of Israel, number one. But
then at the same time the Israelis spy
on the United States.
And so it's hard to work as a partner
with a country when you know that
they're spying on you and they're
actively trying to recruit your
colleagues
to be spies for the Mossad.
So it's it's very difficult to have
respect.
You know, it's very difficult to share
the same
goals or interests when you know that
deep down they really don't want to be
your friend.
They just want your secrets.